<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>java on Dev Utkarsh</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/tags/java/</link><description>Recent content in java on Dev Utkarsh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.devutkarsh.com/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>API-microgateway service using Netflix Zuul on Java</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/api-microgateway-service-using-netflix-zuul-on-java/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/api-microgateway-service-using-netflix-zuul-on-java/</guid><description>How to write an api-service or edge-service or api-gateway? So we are here today to write a gateway microservice using Springboot framework, Netflix&amp;rsquo;s Zuul library, and our never-getting-old programming language Java. As a part of this development, we will be using Gradle to build this together and prepare the Docker image out of it.
If you are not sure yet, what this api-service is going to help you with, I recommend reading out What is api-microgateway?</description></item><item><title>Edge Authentication in Microservices</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/edge-authentication-in-microservices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/edge-authentication-in-microservices/</guid><description>What is edge authentication? Edge authentication or authorization is a way to validate all the requests before they reach the actual microservice or private networks i.e. at the edge. This is done at a global level for all the services, so that individual microservice do not have to handle the authentication or authorization on thier own.
This removes the security overhead from all microservices so that they can communicate insecurely in the mesh within a private network and focus on only concerned business logic.</description></item></channel></rss>