<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Dev Utkarsh</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Dev Utkarsh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.devutkarsh.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kisi Subah</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/kisi-subah/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/kisi-subah/</guid><description>A night of September 2018 and some random weekend when I was chilling with my friends at a house party in Bangalore. Most of the weekends (and even weekdays) you will find almost all IT employees here grabbing a drink and catching up with friends or colleagues. So just like everyone else, I was enjoying it too. Though on the other side of the story there was someone waiting for that daily call and I was breaking a habit tonight, which pissed her off.</description></item><item><title>Kho Gaya Hu</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/kho-gaya-hu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/kho-gaya-hu/</guid><description>It was in 2014 when I had finished my engineering and was looking out for jobs. It was tough time when everything I got felt like was falling apart. As music always have been an amazing savior, came to rescue, and Kho Gaya Hu was born. It took merely 40 minutes to get the music and lyrics. It all just came naturally. I was alone in the flat tinkering with my guitar in hot June afternoon.</description></item><item><title>Streaming AWS S3 objects in AWS EKS cluster</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/streaming-aws-s3-objects-in-aws-eks-cluster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/streaming-aws-s3-objects-in-aws-eks-cluster/</guid><description>Java spring-boot microservice to read objects from AWS S3 bucket that can be accessed by other microservices over HTTP I recently came across a requirement to host static content for my microservices running on the AWS EKS cluster.
Since there were multiple services that will be accessing different objects so I thought to create a common S3 bucket for hosting and gave S3ReadAccess to my cluster.</description></item><item><title>How to create a Kubernetes cluster on AWS EKS</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/how-to-create-a-kubernetes-cluster-on-aws-eks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/how-to-create-a-kubernetes-cluster-on-aws-eks/</guid><description>Using self-managed Amazon EC2 nodes (No Fargate) To create a kubernetes cluster on aws eks, we would be using the aws cli and eksctl that needs to be installed on your local command line as a pre-requisite.
Your aws cli should be configured with the access token and secret of your aws console and your user should have right aws IAM access role.
Now as you have this ready, we will be creating a config file named as cluster.</description></item><item><title>Using AWS S3 and Lambda to process file chunks</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/using-aws-s3-and-lambda-to-process-file-chunks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/using-aws-s3-and-lambda-to-process-file-chunks/</guid><description>Merge file parts/chunks in S3 on receive - PUT object by invoking lambda Sending files in chunks over the network is most common because it&amp;rsquo;s easy to apply a retry mechanism over failed parts. On receiving all the parts then the parts or chunks are merged together to create one single file. We all know how frustrating is to see download failing at 99%.
Data chunking is the most common technique used by your wifi to send you data packets.</description></item><item><title>How high is technology in 2021?</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/how-high-is-technology-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/how-high-is-technology-in-2021/</guid><description>Understanding the world of cloud computing and high-speed internet. Technology has moved to the cloud, it was just 11 years ago when I was puzzled by the word cloud computing. Luckily back then I had access to free internet and Google search engine to kill my curiosity.
It was when I was sitting copying all the pictures from the college fest to a pen drive so that we can share them with everyone else.</description></item><item><title>API-microgateway service using Netflix Zuul on Java</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/api-microgateway-service-using-netflix-zuul-on-java/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/api-microgateway-service-using-netflix-zuul-on-java/</guid><description>How to write an api-service or edge-service or api-gateway? So we are here today to write a gateway microservice using Springboot framework, Netflix&amp;rsquo;s Zuul library, and our never-getting-old programming language Java. As a part of this development, we will be using Gradle to build this together and prepare the Docker image out of it.
If you are not sure yet, what this api-service is going to help you with, I recommend reading out What is api-microgateway?</description></item><item><title>API Gateway vs Edge Proxy service vs API Microgateway</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/api-gateway-vs-edge-proxy-service-vs-api-microgateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/api-gateway-vs-edge-proxy-service-vs-api-microgateway/</guid><description>Routing request to different microservices from a single REST endpoint Having a single entry point for your all backend microservices in your application comes in handy for the frontend applications. The front end just needs to know one domain to reach for anything. Since in distributed architecture, we have multiple services running, it becomes easier for the frontend client to communicate only with one gateway only without knowing what happens in the background.</description></item><item><title>Hampi - World Heritage Site</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/hampi-world-heritage-site/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/hampi-world-heritage-site/</guid><description>I HOLD THAT A STRONGLY MARKED PERSONALITY CAN INFLUENCE DESCENDANTS FOR GENERATIONS. ~ BEATRIX POTTER Hampi and the lost stories in the ruins. It is a beautifully broken Hindu kingdom along Tungabhadra river which is just 300km from Bangalore. So one weekend I planned to travel and went with my friends to reveal the history behind. We took a direct train from Yeshwantpur railway station on a Friday evening to Hosapete to cover the most of the journey and then took an auto rickshaw to travel the remaining 10km and arrived at Hampi on a warm Saturaday morning.</description></item><item><title>Auli &amp; Joshimath - Snow &amp; Skii India</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/auli-joshimath-snow-skii-india/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/auli-joshimath-snow-skii-india/</guid><description>WELL, I KNOW NOW. I KNOW A LITTLE MORE HOW MUCH A SIMPLE THING LIKE A SNOWFALL CAN MEAN TO A PERSON. ~ SYLVIA PLATH Well, I started pretty early in the morning at 4am. I had not slept this night. This was a sudden plan and urge to visit Auli that I went to travel on. Rishikesh was already doing so good but I the wanderlust.</description></item><item><title>Pondicherry - Last French Colony</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/pondicherry-last-french-colony/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/pondicherry-last-french-colony/</guid><description>LIFE IS SOMETHING WE ALL ARE SCARED OF. I have been to Pondicherry twice. Once with my friend and band&amp;rsquo;s drummer, Ankit Godle and next time with my friends from Bangalore. Both time from I travelled from Bangalore, once by bus and next time taking a self-driving car.
The first time I visited was in 2016, when I visited Chennai to meet Ankit for a new song composition.</description></item><item><title>Bhandardara - Mumbai Overview</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/bhandardara-mumbai-overview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/bhandardara-mumbai-overview/</guid><description>A VILLAGE IS A HIVE OF GLASS, WHERE NOTHING UNOBSERVED CAN PASS. ~ CHARLES SPURGEON Just the end of 2014 after graduating from college, I started my first job in Mumbai. While I was just a learner of professionalism at workplace, I met many like minded acquaintances and became friends in no time. After all the amazing trainings were done, the 2 month program had also created amazing friendships.</description></item><item><title>Wayanad - Kerala</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/wayanad-kerala/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/wayanad-kerala/</guid><description>LIFE IS EITHER A DARING ADVENTURE OR NOTHING. There was a time when I wanted to escape office. It was a weekend of November 2015 and we had no plans. Recently one of my friends had shifted to Mysore for work. So I asked my flatmate &amp;amp; friend Aprit, if he is interested in visiting traveling to Mysore to meet our common friend Adarsh. We left at night and took an early morning train from Yeshwantpur Railway Station, Bangalore to Mysore.</description></item><item><title>Chikmagalur, Karnataka - The Mullayanagiri Trek</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/chikmagalur-karnataka-the-mullayanagiri-trek/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/chikmagalur-karnataka-the-mullayanagiri-trek/</guid><description>IT IS BETTER TO TRAVEL WELL THAN TO ARRIVE. ~ BUDDHA One fine weekend me and my friends from Bangalore planned to visit the famous Chikmagalur district. So I called them up on a Friday night and took a government bus on a Saturday morning. It was 4-5 hours journey from Bangalore. We all just had a bagpack with only clothes and essentials.
We took a lodge instead of getting into any fancy hotel.</description></item><item><title>Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh - City of Nawabs</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/lucknow-uttar-pradesh-city-of-nawabs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/lucknow-uttar-pradesh-city-of-nawabs/</guid><description>THERE&amp;amp;rsquo;S SOMETHING THAT HAPPENS TO YOU WHEN YOU COME BACK TO YOUR HOMETOWN. ~JOSEPH DOUGHERTY  Ah! Lucknow, the most amazing city of memories. Such a calm city with kids playing cricket at almost every corner. That&amp;rsquo;s how I grew up at least. It has changed with time too, but still holds such a beauty every time I visit. The amazing Charbagh Railway Station to iconic Aminabad. With progressive Gomti Nagar to chilled Jankipuram and from Aashiyana to Bara Imambara.</description></item><item><title>Varanasi or Kashi - City of Ghats</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/varanasi-or-kashi-city-of-ghats/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/varanasi-or-kashi-city-of-ghats/</guid><description>ADVENTURE IS WORTHWHILE. ~ ARISTOTLE It was just two days after my birthday. I was in Lucknow for Diwali and had booked a ticket via Varanasi to Bangalore to travel back after vacations. Well that was the plan, and my train was supposed to be in Varanasi 5 hours before my flight. And I must tell, you can never predict what&amp;rsquo;s gonna happen next.
The winters had already hit the North India and that means it will be sooner when the visibility gonna go down with dense fog.</description></item><item><title>Nainital - City of Lakes</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/nainital-city-of-lakes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/nainital-city-of-lakes/</guid><description>NOT EVERY LAKE DREAMS TO BE AN OCEAN. BLESSED ARE THE ONES WHO ARE HAPPY WITH WHOM THEY ARE. ~ MEHMET MURAT ILDAN Nainital happened like an impromptu. I was in Delhi meeting few friends when the two of decided to visit Nainital the next day. Also, it was a weekend. We booked bus tickets and started next day in the evening around 9pm. We reached Kathgodam the next morning and from there we got on the shared taxis that run between Kathgodam and Nainital.</description></item><item><title>Dawki - And the Bangladesh Border</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/dawki-and-the-bangladesh-border/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/dawki-and-the-bangladesh-border/</guid><description>ALWAYS DO WHAT YOU ARE AFRAID TO DO. ~ RALPH WALDO EMERSON Boat Ride in Dawki River
It was 11th of October 2017, I had already been tired with solo journey and exhausting treks of Cherrapunji. I had planned to travel to Dawki today. It was hardly 90Kms from here and Google Maps kept me informed that it won&amp;rsquo;t take you more than 3 hours to reach the spot.</description></item><item><title>Cherrapunji or Sohra - October Drizzles</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/cherrapunji-or-sohra-october-drizzles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/cherrapunji-or-sohra-october-drizzles/</guid><description>THE WAY I SEE IT, IF YOU WANT THE RAINBOW, YOU GOTTA PUT UP WITH THE RAIN. ~ DOLLY PARTON Laitlum Grand Canyon View from Shillong - Cherrapunji Highway
Once I started for Cherrapunji, it was cold morning already with no sun and the sky covered with blanket of cloud. The sky was white and I knew that it is going to rain today. Also, the Geography books that I read since my childhood told me, Cherrapunji receives the highest rainfall every year.</description></item><item><title>Shillong - Rock Capital of India</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/shillong-rock-capital-of-india/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/shillong-rock-capital-of-india/</guid><description>I THINK THAT’S WHAT IT IS WITH ROCK MUSIC. IT HELPS YOU HANG TOUGH, I GUESS. ~ ANGUS YOUNG Malki Grounds, Shillong
What a beautiful drive to Shillong from Guwahati, it took around 3 hours to cover the 100 km stretch. It was drizzling when I started, got a little drenched as well. While I reached the city, I saw an amazing evening with an ongoing football match at Malki Grounds, meanwhile the sun was setting down.</description></item><item><title>Meghalaya - My first solo trip</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/meghalaya-my-first-solo-trip/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/meghalaya-my-first-solo-trip/</guid><description>GREAT THINGS NEVER CAME FROM COMFORT ZONES. There was a time I loved computers and Internet. Well a pretty neat invention of all time, getting us all done with a click. From having a virtual social life to setting up business, from making travels plan easier to flying to Moon &amp;amp; back. Yes! We can have it all. But what we have? A machine holding us from all the beautiful adventures out there and making us well assured that this life is easy and amazing at the same time.</description></item></channel></rss>