<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>meghalaya on Dev Utkarsh</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/tags/meghalaya/</link><description>Recent content in meghalaya on Dev Utkarsh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.devutkarsh.com/tags/meghalaya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dawki - And the Bangladesh Border</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/dawki-and-the-bangladesh-border/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/dawki-and-the-bangladesh-border/</guid><description>ALWAYS DO WHAT YOU ARE AFRAID TO DO. ~ RALPH WALDO EMERSON Boat Ride in Dawki River
It was 11th of October 2017, I had already been tired with solo journey and exhausting treks of Cherrapunji. I had planned to travel to Dawki today. It was hardly 90Kms from here and Google Maps kept me informed that it won&amp;rsquo;t take you more than 3 hours to reach the spot.</description></item><item><title>Cherrapunji or Sohra - October Drizzles</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/cherrapunji-or-sohra-october-drizzles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/cherrapunji-or-sohra-october-drizzles/</guid><description>THE WAY I SEE IT, IF YOU WANT THE RAINBOW, YOU GOTTA PUT UP WITH THE RAIN. ~ DOLLY PARTON Laitlum Grand Canyon View from Shillong - Cherrapunji Highway
Once I started for Cherrapunji, it was cold morning already with no sun and the sky covered with blanket of cloud. The sky was white and I knew that it is going to rain today. Also, the Geography books that I read since my childhood told me, Cherrapunji receives the highest rainfall every year.</description></item><item><title>Shillong - Rock Capital of India</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/shillong-rock-capital-of-india/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/shillong-rock-capital-of-india/</guid><description>I THINK THAT’S WHAT IT IS WITH ROCK MUSIC. IT HELPS YOU HANG TOUGH, I GUESS. ~ ANGUS YOUNG Malki Grounds, Shillong
What a beautiful drive to Shillong from Guwahati, it took around 3 hours to cover the 100 km stretch. It was drizzling when I started, got a little drenched as well. While I reached the city, I saw an amazing evening with an ongoing football match at Malki Grounds, meanwhile the sun was setting down.</description></item><item><title>Meghalaya - My first solo trip</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/meghalaya-my-first-solo-trip/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/meghalaya-my-first-solo-trip/</guid><description>GREAT THINGS NEVER CAME FROM COMFORT ZONES. There was a time I loved computers and Internet. Well a pretty neat invention of all time, getting us all done with a click. From having a virtual social life to setting up business, from making travels plan easier to flying to Moon &amp;amp; back. Yes! We can have it all. But what we have? A machine holding us from all the beautiful adventures out there and making us well assured that this life is easy and amazing at the same time.</description></item></channel></rss>