<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloud on Dev Utkarsh</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/tags/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in cloud on Dev Utkarsh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.devutkarsh.com/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How high is technology in 2021?</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/how-high-is-technology-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/how-high-is-technology-in-2021/</guid><description>Understanding the world of cloud computing and high-speed internet. Technology has moved to the cloud, it was just 11 years ago when I was puzzled by the word cloud computing. Luckily back then I had access to free internet and Google search engine to kill my curiosity.
It was when I was sitting copying all the pictures from the college fest to a pen drive so that we can share them with everyone else.</description></item><item><title>API Gateway vs Edge Proxy service vs API Microgateway</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/api-gateway-vs-edge-proxy-service-vs-api-microgateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/api-gateway-vs-edge-proxy-service-vs-api-microgateway/</guid><description>Routing request to different microservices from a single REST endpoint Having a single entry point for your all backend microservices in your application comes in handy for the frontend applications. The front end just needs to know one domain to reach for anything. Since in distributed architecture, we have multiple services running, it becomes easier for the frontend client to communicate only with one gateway only without knowing what happens in the background.</description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/hello-world/</guid><description>Where is this blog coming from? The biggest driving force will always be curiosity, and if you have it, your focus will lead you where you want to be!
I have always been curios to explore, the wild in nature, the depth in music and everything else. Always trying to learn more and grasp knowledge while grow spritually. But that becomes problematic if you try to hop on multiple boats because time is quantifiable.</description></item></channel></rss>