<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloud on Dev Utkarsh</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/tags/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in cloud on Dev Utkarsh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.devutkarsh.com/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FinOps 101 - Saving Databricks Cost</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/finops-101-saving-databricks-cost/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/finops-101-saving-databricks-cost/</guid><description>FinOps for Data Engineers: Stop Wasting Money by Using Databricks Smarter Databricks has revolutionized how data teams handle big data, machine learning, and analytics by offering a unified cloud platform with powerful distributed computing. But here’s the tough truth:
Many companies are burning cloud money unnecessarily because developers are using Databricks notebooks as an all-in-one development environment — even for tasks that don’t need cluster power.
This article explores why this behavior is costly, how to shift towards local-first development, and how to use the Databricks CLI to push only the final, distributed workloads to the cloud — saving your company potentially thousands of dollars per month.</description></item><item><title>How high is technology in 2021?</title><link>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/how-high-is-technology-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.devutkarsh.com/how-high-is-technology-in-2021/</guid><description>Understanding the world of cloud computing and high-speed internet. Technology has moved to the cloud, it was just 11 years ago when I was puzzled by the word cloud computing. Luckily back then I had access to free internet and Google search engine to kill my curiosity.
It was when I was sitting copying all the pictures from the college fest to a pen drive so that we can share them with everyone else.</description></item></channel></rss>